大家好，美丽的人们，欢迎收看这段视频，我们将在这里讨论如何
Hello you beautiful people and welcome to this video where we're going to be talking about how you can
下载软件包的源代码。
download the source code for packages.
所以目前我们所能做的就是下载并安装预编译的二进制软件包，但是我们
So at the minute all we've been able to do is download and install precompiled binary packages but we're
感兴趣的是我们如何才能获得源代码，这样我们就可以自由地行使
interested in how we might be able to go about getting source code so we can exercise the freedoms that
自由软件给了我们。
free software gives us.
要做到这一点实际上是一个非常简单的过程，或者作为管理员要做的事情。
And it's actually a very easy process in order to do so or what to do is as an administrator.
因此，使用sudo命令在natto中打开劈开，在c劈开apt劈开上打开文档列表文件。
So with the sudo command open up in natto the slash at c slash apt slash sourses doc list file.
好的，现在在这里，当您输入密码时，您将打开一个配置文件，即包
Ok now in here when you enter your password you're going to be opening up a configuration file the package
管理器使用来确定它下载的存储库和程序包文件。
manager uses to determine which repositories and which package files it downloads.
换句话说，它下载的是哪个源。
In other words which source is it downloads.
好的，我们在这里要做的是，您会注意到有几行以Debb source开头
OK so what we're going to do in here is you'll notice that there are lines that start with Debb source
或者Debb破折号S或C，这些行前面有一个散列。
or Debb dash S or C and those lines have a hash in front of them.
我想要做的是删除适当行上的所有散列。
What I want to do is I want to just delete all those hashes on those appropriate lines.
这将激活您的包管理器能够下载的功能
And what this will do is it will activate the ability for your package manager to be able to download
源代码，默认情况下处于停用状态，基本上只是为了节省效率。
source code which is deactivated by default just to save efficiency basically.
所以我们要去看“还没做过的事”。
So we're going to Haven't done that.
我要按0中的Ctrl保存文件，或者按X的X Ctrl退出。
I'm going to press control in 0 to save the file or press X control of X to exit.
那么我们所做的就是我们已经对软件包管理器说，嘿，为什么不继续下载
So then what we've done is we've said to the package manager hey why don't you go ahead and download
软件包列出了包含源代码的列表。
the package lists that contain source code.
好的，但是为了能够把这些东西放进缓存，我们必须更新我们的现金。
Ok but to be able to get those things in the cache we've got to update our cash.
好的，我所做的就是sudo apt获取更新，它将继续并开始下载所有源代码
OK so all I was do sudo apt get updates and it's going to go ahead and start downloading all the source
包裹在这里。
packages here.
因此您可以看到，这是在将所有源包安装到缓存中。
So you can see that this is is installing all the source packages into cache.
这是一件非常有用的事情，因为现在我们可以了，我们几乎已经准备好能够下载源代码了。
This is a very useful thing because now we can we're almost ready to be able to download source code.
好的，在我们可以下载源代码之前，我们需要再安装一个软件包，以便安装
OK so before we can download source code we need to install one more package which is so to get installed
将是DASH DEV包DP K.G.DASH DEV。
is going to be the package dash dev package the DP K.G. dash dev.
你安装了，当它问你的时候，你输入YES，然后我们就到了，我们已经成功了，现在就要开始了
You install that you type yes when it asks you and there we are we've managed to now it's going to go
然后下载并解压缩该软件包，现在我们可以继续安装源代码了。
ahead and download and unpack that package and now we can go ahead and install source code.
从字面上看就是这么简单。
It's literally that simple.
好的，我们一直在摆弄我转移到桌面上的消费税包裹，我们一直在摆弄
OK so we've been messing around with the excise package I made over to the desktop and we've been messing
带着消费税包裹到处跑。
around with the excise package.
我们怎样才能弄到锻炼套餐或锻炼计划的源代码呢？
How can we get the source code for the for the excise package or the exercise program.
它包含在x11应用程序包中。
Well it's contained in the x 11 apps package.
因此，如果我们使用sudo apt get，并且我们过去是正确安装的，那么我们确实可以正确安装X11应用程序。
So if we do sudo apt get and we used to do install right we do install X 11 apps right.
这就是获取预编译二进制版本的方法。
That's how you'd get the pre-compiled binary version.
但是如果你想要得到源代码，你就会发现，它有点像是，而不是安装，只要把源代码放进去就行了
But if you want to get the source code it sort of instead of install just put source and you'll see
它会继续下载这些包以包含源代码。
that it goes ahead and downloads these packages to contain source code.
现在，我们实际上可以继续使用CD输入这些内容。
Now we can actually go ahead and enter these using CD.
因此，如果我们将CD放入包中并四处看看，我们可以看到这里有一个文件夹，用于存放X Eyes和
So if we CD into the package and take a look around we can see there's is a folder here for X eyes and
如果我们看一下X Eyes，这里会看到CD X Eyes，我们已经获得了该练习的源代码
if we take a look in X eyes a CD X eyes will be seen here that we've got the source code for the exercise
程序，所以您可以看到我们已经有了配置文件，可以用来配置新的C编译器。
program so you can see we've got our config file that we can can use to configure our new C-compiler.
但是我们现在感兴趣的是这个附加部分Dotsie，它实际上是
But what we're interested in right now is this excise Dotsie which is actually the source code for the
练习程序，我们可以在这里看一看，并阅读练习程序的源代码。
exercise program and we can take a look in here and read the source code for the exercise program.
从字面上看就是这么简单。
It's literally that simple.
好的。
OK.
我们所要做的就是继续更改我们的劈开ETSI劈开运营劈开来源。
All we had to do was go ahead and change our slash ETSI slash ops slash sources.
Dart去年秋天在这里只需取消注释前面有散列的所有行
Dart last fall and in here just uncomment all the lines that had that had a hash in front of them for
黛布线人。
Debb source.
这些都是允许您实际下载源代码以查看和评论所有内容的存储库
And those are the repositories that allow you to actually download source code to view and comment all
然后使用sudo apt更新您的缓存，然后获取更新，然后下载所有新的
of those and then update your cache using sudo apt get updates then what you've downloaded all the new
LESS我们要做的就是安装IS，安装DP K.G.dev包，然后您就可以进入那里了
less We've got to do is install the is install the DP K.G. dev package and then you get to go in there
从现在开始，如果你想下载任何源代码，你所要做的就是sudo apt get source
from now on if you ever want to download any source code and all you've got to do is sudo apt get source
然后是包名。
and then a package name.
好的。
OK.
这就是您需要知道的全部内容，以便能够下载和玩弄源代码。
And that is all you need to know in order to be able to download and play around with source code.
但是您应该记住的一件事是，如果您进入源代码包中，并且您实际上
But one thing that you should bear in mind is that if you go into the source code packages and you actually
编译它们您将失去安装它们的能力，这样您将失去保持更新的能力
compile them you'll lose the ability to install them that way you'll lose the ability to keep them updated
和你的套餐经理在一起。
with your package manager.
因此，如果您可以选择通过软件包管理器安装软件包，也可以选择从
So therefore if you have the choice to install a package through the package manager or install it from
源代码请确保您通过包管理器和存储库(而不是通过存储库)安装它
source make sure that you install it through the package manager and through the repositories rather
而不是自己编辑。
than compiling it yourself.
但是，这是一种非常酷的方式，可以继续查看代码是如何工作的，也许还可以合并
But this is a really cool way to be able to go ahead and take a look at how code works and maybe incorporate
把它放在你的项目里。
it in your projects.